[Music]
what's up everybody and welcome back in
another video of drama builders
and today we are going to do the
unboxing
and reviewing the new air viper airbrush
from ammo by mick geminis i don't know
if i pronounce it correctly but so this
is their latest model the previous model
was the cobra this is the air viper and
this one has a 0.2 needle by default so
the box
is already looking uh
kind of neat
it looks like the airbrush can take on
heavy duty paints
it's aluminum
very
well crafted and here on the side flip
you have some specs let's take a closer
look at it so the specs are it's a
double action airbrush of course uh most
of the airbrushes nowadays are double
action airbrush
uh it has a 0.2 uh nozzle needle you get
a 1.8 milliliter paint cup which is
plenty for the common modeler you got
some teflon seals which is
especially good if you are using lacquer
paints
and of course it will last longer
as it mentioned long live material
components
it also has a reversible spare tips for
better airbrush performance and easy
cleaning while in use this is something
of course that i'm looking forward to
because if you do refine detail you
always end up with a dried paint uh
blocking the needle and this airbrush
can be used for uh yeah acrylics enamel
lacquers inked dyes
irritants and so on so let's crack this
open and see what's in there
so you have the manual here which comes
in a different languages which is pretty
neat i'm going to have a look at the
dutch
manual i'm from belgium i'm speaking
flemish here you have some
specifications about all the parts how
to use it some tips and tricks
yeah
very valuable information
so here you have
your nozzle wrench
which you use to remove the nozzle of
course
and here you have the yeah very nice
looking airbrush
you have the logo engraved there the air
fiber 0.2 yeah it's a beautiful looking
airbrush with the gold and the chrome
which works
yeah
good together just fine it's very eye
appealing
and as i said it reminds me of a badger
airbrush
here you have an
plastic
nozzle cover which protects the needle
here you have your plastic seal cup with
your 1.8 milliliter
cup first thing i noticed is of course
the
well thought needle guard cap that you
have here which you can remove and
put on in reverse but i wouldn't suggest
that because if you drop your
airbrush it could damage the needle and
also the airflow that comes out
is not
hindered or bothered by
some other closed needle caps that you
have and here you have your
dual action trigger with some dents
you can
push it
back and forth you push it down
to let the air out and you pull it back
for the paint to come out and it
responds very smoothly on the back you
have yeah the limiter which controls how
far back you can uh pull the trigger
if you tighten it you see
that this is closing and
you cannot pull it back as far which is
great for uh yeah fine details fine
lines so for repeatable consistent
things this is a great yeah very nice
looking
airbrush it feels good in the hand it's
very well balanced so the next step of
course is to load up some paint and see
how everything works so here i have a
printed
part that i'm not going to use anymore
which is perfectly for testing here we
have a black primer it's also created by
ammo make i got my airbrush connected to
the compressor so we are going to
fill the cup with this black primer
so let's uh prime this uh this is an arm
piece for those who might wonder what it
is
this is an um
the
upper left arm of the classic iron man
so let's go ahead and
put on the black primer
it's always best to put on several light
coats instead of one or two
thick coats because you might end up
covering or hiding some
details
[Music]
so the first coat is on there
i'm just going to push
the trigger to blow some error
which helps drying it faster
[Applause]
so don't pull back
because you're going to put on paint on
there of course so just
pull it to release some air
[Applause]
okay so now the first coat is dried we
are going to put a second coat of the
black primer
[Music]
so now we are going to put on uh the red
as
yeah my primary
paint
so let's take out the airbrush which i
clean of course i already have shaken
the red thoroughly
so i'm going to put on the red and try
to create some highlights here and there
[Music]
for the second coat we are going to use
the red again and highlight
some more
[Music]
so you see the upper part of the arm
is much bright a little bit brighter
than the upper part which yeah mostly
captures all these shadows so the arm is
dry the red is dry and for the last coat
we are going to put some extra highlight
from the top
i'm going to use the same red
with a little pinch of
orange and as you can see the
ammo make paint have a little stirring
ball in there so for this method it's
very important not to hold your airbrush
close but keep and spray it from the
distance so
it's a very very thin coat that you have
to apply
[Music]
i don't know if you can see it on camera
but it's a very small detail but it
makes a huge difference
so the paint job on the arm is done the
airbrush had no problems either with
very fine lines fine surfaces
the airflow was
fluently consistently every time overall
this airbrush performed very well
so there you have it guys afterwards the
cleanup was a very
easy quick straightforward you just
remove this
handle
untighten the screw so you can remove
the needle clean it
and within a minute you are ready to
continue your work
and as with all reviews it's important
to talk about the positives and the
negatives and to be honest
for the time being i haven't found a
negative point about this airbrush
the price is around 130 euros which
could be the only negative
thing that i
might find because it maybe not be
accessible for everybody but again
with good quality comes a price of
course overall the performance is really
good the manual comes in different
languages which is always handy and it
provides clearly how to use the errors
you have your parts overview all the
necessary information is in there
so that was it for today i hoped you
liked this review you learned something
maybe you might consider of buying this
i will put a link in the description to
their online store if you want to buy
this airbrush
personally
it's very versatile even for beginners
or for experts you might consider adding
this one to your list
if you have any questions about this
airbrush
please put your comments down below i
will be happy to answer them for you if
you haven't subscribed to my channel yet
please do and don't forget to hit that
notification button so you don't miss
out on any new videos
so that was uh it for today guys thank
you for watching and i will see you all
in my next video drama builders signing
out bye everybody
[Music]